Let's see a question stem.
We have a newborn; he's going to defend
his anchoring fibrils.
There's going to be a type VII collagen.
And they're going to ask you, "Hey, what's the skin finding?"
The answer is going to be blisters.
So anchoring fibers should make you think
of the hemidesmosomes.
I don't know why, but I like to think of a little ladder.
You know, the ladder kind of looks like this
and this looks like an "H."
And I like to think of this, at the very bottom,
as an anchor.
It'll tether your basal keratinocytes
of the epidermis to the dermis.
There's your "H," your hemidesmosome.
And that's going to be a type VII collagen.
And so the epidermis will separate from the dermis
and you get a blister.
If you don't have that anchoring, you don't have that.
Then that's what you get: mechanical fragility
of that dermal epidermal junction.
Some trap answers that you might see
would be like a rash for that.
You think of, like, Job's syndrome or atopic dermatitis,
maybe even West Cod Algae.
So that would be like your red patches,
not your blisters from structural weakness.
There would also be no vesicle rupture.
Not easy bruising that would make you think of, like, scurvy,
vitamin C deficiency.
They could say keratodermas or ichthyosis.
"Ichthy" makes you think of a fish, a little like fish skin.
That's going to be your thickened skin
that's due to this straight-up stratum corneum buildup.
So that's just a different disease: ulcers.
That would be full-thickness loss of your epidermis
that exposes the dermis.
So you'd see that in, like, lupus, for instance,
but this is not that.
We're looking at a structural defect here.
So epidermolysis bullosa dystrophica
is going to be a type VII collagen defect
causing your blisters, especially through trauma or friction.
Diagnosed on skin biopsy with immunofluorescence.
Here's your educational pearl for the day.
We'll see you guys in the next video.
```