Did you know that by six months, your mom's antibodies have already worn off?
So if you have Bruton's agammaglobulinemia, then you are flying so low and breaking.
So your bone marrow is going to make these B cells.
And then the BTK gene is needed for the transition from pre-B cells to the mature B cells.
And if you have a mutation there, like in Bruton's agammaglobulinemia,
then the B cells are going to rest in that pre-B stage.
And so that means you get no plasma cells, no antibodies, no immunoglobulins.
So if you see the electrophoresis graph, it's going to be super low for the gamma.
So here's our practice question.
We got a nine-month-old boy who has been to the hospital a couple of times.
Could be anywhere from nine months to ten or eleven.
Pneumonia.
We've got some pneumonia; he's been in the hospital a couple of times.
His dad, another male in the family, died of severe infections.
We have absent B cells.
Low, I mean, low levels.
So what are we going to see?
We're going to definitely see absent.
Monoclonal spike.
That would make us think of multiple myeloma.
Beta-gamma bridging.
That's IgA overproduction or cirrhosis.
Broad-based polyclonal increase.
That would be seen in an autoimmune condition.
It's definitely not normal.
So let's think of the buzzwords.
Recurrent pneumonia, H. flu, Staphylococcus aureus, just recurrent pulmonary infections.
Also, just think that if you have a boy with an X-linked disease,
it should cue you into that a little bit too.
So encapsulated organisms, no IgG.
You have poor opsonization.
You have no tonsils or they're absent.
Because those are B-cell dependent organs, or they are underdeveloped.
If you guys found this video helpful, then please like and subscribe.
Definitely hit the bell.
Also, consider subscribing because we're going to be giving a
subscription to our new platform, which you'll like to explore better.
Well, good luck studying for that.
```