Let's see a question stem where you have a newborn; he's got a
defect in his anchoring fibrils. This is going to be your type
VII collagen, and they're going to ask you, "Hey, what's the skin finding?" The
answer is going to be blisters. So anchoring fibrils should make you think of the
hemidesmosomes. I don't know why, but I like to think of a little ladder.
You know, a ladder kind of looks like this, and this looks like an "H," and I
like to think of this as, at the very bottom, like an anchor. It'll tether your
basal keratinocytes of the epidermis to the dermis. So there's your "H," your
type VII collagen, and so the epidermis will
separate from the dermis, and you get a blister. If you don't have that anchoring,
if you don't have that, then that's what you get: mechanical fragility of that
dermal-epidermal junction. Some trap answers that you might see would be like
a rash; for that, you think of like Job's syndrome or atopic dermatitis,
maybe even vasculitis. So that would be like your red patches, not your
blisters from structural weakness. There'd also be no vesicle rupture,
not easy bruising; that would make you think of like scurvy, vitamin C
deficiency. They could say keratodermas or ichthyosis. "Ichthy" makes you think of
like fish, little like fish skin. That's going to be your thickened skin that's
due to this stratum corneum buildup. So that's just a different disease. Ulcers,
that'd be full-thickness loss of your epidermis that exposes the dermis. So you'd see that in like
lupus, for instance, but this is not that. We're looking at a structural defect here.
So epidermolysis bullosa dystrophica. It's going to be a type VII collagen defect
causing your blisters, especially through trauma or friction. Diagnosed on skin biopsy with
immunofluorescence. There's your educational pearl for the day. We'll see you guys in the next video.