Did you know that by six months your mom's antibodies have already worn off?
And so if you have Bruton's agammaglobulinemia, then you are flying low immunologically speaking.
So your bone marrow is going to make these B cells.
And then the BTK gene is needed for the transition from pre-B cells to immature B cells.
And if you have a mutation there, like X-linked Bruton's agammaglobulinemia,
then the B cells are going to rest in that pre-B stage.
And so that means you get no plasma cells, no antibodies, no immunoglobulins.
And so if you see the electrophoresis graph, it's going to be very low for the gamma globulin.
So here's our practice question.
We have a nine-month-old boy who has been to the hospital a couple of times,
could be anywhere from nine months to ten or eleven.
Pneumonia.
He's got some pneumonia and has been in the hospital a couple of times.
His dad, another male in the family, died of severe infections.
We have absent CD19 cells and low immunoglobulin levels.
So what are we going to see?
We're definitely going to see absence.
A monoclonal spike would make us think of multiple myeloma.
Beta-gamma bridging indicates IgA overproduction
or cirrhosis, broad-based polyclonal increase.
That would be seen in an autoimmune condition, and it's definitely not normal.
So let's think of the buzzy buzzwords.
Strep pneumoniae, H. influenzae, Staphylococcus aureus, just recurrent respiratory infections.
Also, if you have a boy with an X-linked disease,
that should already key you into that a little bit too.
So encapsulated organisms, no IgG.
So you have poor opsonization.
You have no tonsils or lymphoid tissue, right?
Because those are B cell-dependent organs that are underdeveloped.
If you found this video helpful, then please like and subscribe.
It definitely helps out the channel.
Also consider subscribing because we're going to be giving out free subscriptions
to our new platform, which is like UWorld, but a little bit better.
It uses artificial intelligence to pinpoint your weaknesses.
Well, good luck studying for Step.
We'll see you in the next one.