Constrictive pericarditis. So we think of an increased JVD, also a pericardial knock,
and Kussmaul's sign. Equalization of diastolic pressure is also going to be seen there.
So you see the increased JVP because of the impaired right heart filling. In cirrhosis,
your JVP is normally going to be normal or low, even if you've got ascites or edema,
because that's driven by hypoalbuminemia and portal hypertension. So let's imagine you've got some
thick, fibrotic pericardium. What's that going to do? It's going to restrict your diastolic
filling of the heart. That's going to lead to an elevated diastolic pressure and also an equalization
of all the pressures in the four chambers. That'll cause hepatic congestion, peripheral edema, and
ascites that can mimic your cirrhosis. And so constrictive pericarditis can mimic cirrhosis.
But the difference here, the difference is going to be these jugular veins because the right heart
can't fill because of the stiff pericardium. So you get that Kussmaul's sign, JVP rising.