This is a very important concept: increased carbon dioxide leads to increased cerebral blood flow.
So, CO2 is the most potent cerebral vasodilator.
Yes, that's correct.
In narcotic overdose, we have respiratory depression, decreased respiratory rate, and increased
CO2 in the blood.
This condition is called hypercapnia.
That means we have increased cerebral blood flow.
Respiratory depression results in elevated CO2 levels.
Hypercapnia indicates that cerebral vasodilation is occurring.
We have a fixed intracranial compartment, so the brain's auto-regulation of flow is affected.
This leads to increased intracranial pressure.
If a patient is arousable only with painful stimuli, we should suspect narcotic overdose.
Central hypoventilation leads to increased CO2 and increased vasodilation.
That's it.
That's the secret.
Opioids depress the respiratory center.
This decrease in ventilation causes CO2 to build up.
CO2 can freely cross the blood-brain barrier, combining with water to form carbonic acid,
which dissociates into hydronium ions, leading to local acidosis.
Acidosis triggers vasodilation, increasing cranial blood flow and intracranial pressure if
unchecked.
Hypercapnia causes an increase in hydronium ions (H+), which leads to respiratory acidosis.
Here's a practice question.
A patient is unresponsive after heroin use; the cause is increased perfusion due to respiratory depression and increased CO2.
Decreased systemic vascular resistance (SVR) is seen in septic shock.
Hypoxia triggers a pulmonary response in the brain.
Increased bicarbonate indicates metabolic compensation.