This is a very important concept.
So, increased carbon dioxide leads to increased cerebral blood flow.
CO2 is the most potent cerebral vasodilator.
Yeah, crazy.
In narcotic overdose, we have respiratory depression,
decreased respiratory rate, and increased CO2 in the blood.
It's called hypercapnia.
That means we have increased cerebral blood flow.
Respiratory depression means we have more CO2.
Hypercapnia means you've got some cerebral vasodilation
going on.
We have a fixed intracranial compartment.
The brain's auto-regulation,
flow in a normal progression, pressure.
If a question stem says "arousable,"
only to painful stimuli, then we should think
of narcotic overdose.
Central hypoventilation, increased CO2, increased vasodilation.
That's it.
That's the secret.
Our opioids depress the respiratory center.
This decrease in ventilation causes CO2 to build up.
CO2 will freely cross the blood-brain barrier,
combining with water to form carbonic acid,
which will dissociate into hydronium, and local acidosis
occurs.
Acidosis triggers vasodilation, increased cranial blood flow,
and increased pressure if unchecked.
Hypercapnia causes increased hydronium ions,
which leads to respiratory acidosis.
Here's a practice question.
Unresponsive after heroin: cause of increased perfusion,
respiratory depression, increased CO2.
Decreased systemic vascular resistance, that's in septic shock.
Hypoxia is a pulmonary response, not the brain.
Increased bicarbonate indicates metabolic compensation.
Mean arterial pressure only affects it if it goes outside.
All right, that's all there is.
See you guys in the next video.