Hey guys, here's an example from my Chrome extension that makes this question super easy.
A 68-year-old man with advanced melanoma is receiving antibody treatment.
that blocks receptors on the T cells. Which receptor is it? Well, before, the question looked like this.
And now with my extension, you click it, click this button down here, and it'll load.
It'll tell you, boom, a receptor involved in HIV entry, a receptor on the helper.
A receptor meaning it's on B cells, a receptor that activates T cells,
or a receptor that blocks and helps activate the T cells on cancer.
Well, indeed, that would be your PD-1 ligand. This guy activates this as a B cell, for instance,
and B. So, each of these is the chemoreceptor 5 that binds to your CD4s, and the antagonist there
has been developed and managed to engage HIV, and blockade of your CD4 itself
inhibits T cell activation. So, with this little extension,
you guys can simplify these questions. If you find this helpful, like and subscribe.
Also, you can give this out by clicking the link in the description.
```