Hey everybody, we're gonna break down a step one practice session. Very high yield, so let's start.
40-year-old homeless man with an inflamed spasm and locked jaw. He has a history of drug use and
abduction. What is the path it has taken? Okay, so we have inflamed spasm, open our jaw, we should be
thinking of pre-venous metonymy. That’s what we have; the spores are typically transmitted through a
puncture injury like a splinter or a dirty needle use and what we're gonna do here is we use my
contagion to go up, boom, identify what injury to the skin means. That's gonna be your rabies virus
and so that's through the bite wound and the peripheral nerve signals. So that's not gonna be
your answer, question. We know that this is gonna be tetanus. Why? Because of that jaw. Awesome.
Right, because the toxin spreads in a great way through the lower motor neurons. To the spinal cord and
the spinal cord, it's gonna block your and it causes this spasm of the infection. Right, the
recesses are not. Hey, why is it not B? Contaminated food. Well, our little handy-dandy
chromax hematurgies connects too if you just click the description. This is gonna be contaminated
food to bloodstream. This is a botch. Right, so that's always starting with contaminated food and spasm
rather than sending a typical of your botch. That's why this is not the next infected bloodstream.
So, bloodstream to brain g. That's gonna get bacterial infection causing your brain abscess.
That's with headaches, symptoms like that. So you could think of like staphylococcus aureus
from the wound, and you can go through the bloodstream to the brain as a brain abscess. And so symptoms can vary
but yeah we have to look out for that unilateral headache. Let's look at this one. Throat infection.
Bloodstream nerves. A throat infection: think diphtheria. It's involving the nasopharyngeal
exudate. So with diphtheria, we have to think of that smooth membranous pharyngeal exudate.
And that's gonna be the diphtheria toxin that enters into the system and so that's gonna
cause myositis. So that is not getting part of the battle with diphtheria, which is rich, right.
So it affects the skin, and then the nerves and the brain cells like the CNS are the rabies.
Amnesia of food, botulism especially with the nerve endings. Infected wound,
bacterial infection. That's diphtheria. All right, so now let's see our next one.
Mouth nerve brain area. Okay, so from the mouth, it's going to be the herpes simplex virus that
causes encephalitis in the brain. And so you could classically think of herpes simplex virus type
one that causes your oral labial lesions and it's a super frequent cause of your sporadic and
encephalitis. Meningitis when the virus spreads through what? Trigeminal or the olfactory tract.
So there you'll have, you know, focal neurological deficits, your seizures, your fever,
your inflammation. All right, last one, this is the correct answer. So, we've gone through
systematically identifying what each one is and we know it's going to be F. The reason why is this is
Clostridium tetani. So, a puncture wound then travels retrogradely in a great fashion
to the most part. That's going to be a correct answer. So, tetanus. So, it's the oxygen exchange of
Clostridium tetani. So you transmit it by the spores that are going to be in the skin
via the puncture wound. So it's going to germinate, replicate its tetanus toxin that will spread
retrogradely through the lower motor neurons to the spinal cord and there it is. These interneurons
and cause that spastic paralysis. All right, so that is a breakdown of this question. So once
again, quick recap: rabies. There it is, rabies injury to the skin, nerves, and bones and then here's
botulism. So the food, amnesia, botulism, infected wound to bloodstream to brain tissue
that's a bacterial infection, growth infection, bloodstream nerves, olfactory brain area,
simplex virus, encephalitis and needle and dart pain. If you guys found this helpful, of course
there are a lot of these other AI too well. You can download and simply there's a simplification
button that will explain the four basic cups of the dental diagnosis. You can actually have
a great your doctor's all bits of my this. Maybe all sorts of great. So if this is helpful, then
please consider liking it.
```