Let's see a question stem.
Where you have a newborn, he's got a defect in his
incering fibrils.
This is going to be your type 7 collagen.
And they're going to ask you, hey, what's the skin finding?
The answer is going to be blisters.
So, incering fibers should make you think of the hemidesmizomes.
I don't know why, but I like to think of a little ladder.
You know, a ladder kind of looks like this,
and this is like, looks like an H.
And I like to think of this as at the very bottom,
like an anchor.
It'll tether your basal keratinocytes of the epidermis
to the dermis.
So there's your H, your hemidesmizome.
And that's going to be a type 7 collagen.
And so the epidermis will separate from the dermis,
and you get a blister.
If you don't have that anchoring, if you don't have that,
then that's what you get, mechanical fragility
of that dermal epidermal junction.
Some trap answers that you might see would be like,
like a rash for that you think of like Job's syndrome,
or atopic dermatitis, maybe even whisked algeage.
So that would be like your red patches,
not your blisters from structural weakness.
There'd also be no vesicle rupture.
Not easy bruising that would make you think of like,
scurvy vitamin C deficiency.
They could say, credodermas or ichthyosis.
Icthy makes you think of like fish, little like fish skin.
That's going to be your thickened skin
that's due to the stratum corneum buildup.
So that's just a different disease, ulcers.
That'd be full thick loss of your epidermis
that exposes the dermis.
So you'd see that in like lupus, for instance,
but this is not that.
We're looking at a structural defect here.
So epidermolysis, bulosa dystrophica.
It's going to be a type 7 collagen defect
causing your blisters,
especially through trauma or friction.
Stagnosed.