High-yield step question of the day. Did you know that a single allergen can trigger a system-wide
meltdown in under five minutes? That is the power of IgE crosslinking. Now let's see what my extension
does to these answer choices here. What is meant by autoantibody binding to the epithelial surface?
Pemphigus vulgaris. What is meant by Stevens-Johnson syndrome? Well, that's the cell-mediated
hypersensitivity that the test writers are referring to with B. How about exotoxin-mediated?
Well, yeah, it's exotoxin, but endotoxin-mediated is from gram-negative bacteria.
Now, because of the inflammatory response, exotoxin-mediated is correct because that makes us think of
Staphylococcus aureus. It's called its skin, mast cell degranulation, and is related to allergic reactions.
So let's close that and do a practice question. Now that we know what the buzzy test writers are
trying to get us to think of, we had a patient with hypotension and wheezing near the carrier after
exposure to an allergen. It's IgE-mediated. Which molecular interaction initiates the degranulation
process? The answer? Cross-linking. So anaphylaxis is going to begin with the multivalent antigen
cross-links.