Hey guys, here's an example of how my crime this question is super easy. A 68-year-old man with
advanced disease is receiving antibody treatment that blocks a receptor on the T cell. Which receptor is
it? Well, before the question looked like this, and now with my extension, you click this
button down here, and it'll load and it'll tell you, boom, a receptor involved in HIV, the receptor
on the helper T cell that activates or a receptor that blocks that, when blocked, helps activate.
Well, indeed that would be your PD-1 ligand. This guy activates, this is a B cell for instance, and
HIV uses a receptor 5 to bind to your CD4s, and the antagonist there has been developed into
HIV, and blockade of your CD4 itself inhibits T cell activation. So with this little extension, you
guys can simplify these. If you found this helpful, like and subscribe. Also, you can get this software
by clicking