Six month old infant receives a vaccine that includes a bacterial capsule polysaccharide conjugated to diphtheria toxoid.
What is the immunological advantage conferred by this conjugation?
It's going to be enhanced class switching through the T helper cells.
So infants under two years old can't mount a memory response to plain polysaccharide antigens.
They just can't do it.
But when you conjugate that capsule to a protein like a tetanus toxoid, then it recruits T helper cells
and it enables class switching, affinity maturation, and immunological memory.
So that's how HIV vaccines work.
It's not because of the toxoid, but because of that teamwork.
It's because of that robust T cell dependent immunity.
So let's look at these trap answers.
Ucosyl IGA. It's induced by oral and intranasal vaccines and mucosal infections, not systemic conjugates.
TLR4 recognizes your LPS, not capsular polysaccharides, somatic hypermutation,
the advantage of conjugation as T cell helpers, not diversification.
M cells involved in mucosal antigen sampling, unrelated to conjugate vaccines.
Like and subscribe for a new question every day.