Look at this game. I just played in the Smith-Morah.
E4, C5, then it comes D4.
CD4, we're going to the Smith-Morah gambit.
We continued, and this is kind of a weird transposition,
but the reason I put my queen right here on E2
is because they always missed this tactic right here.
All right? So he missed it.
He's going to get it back soon because I missed this attack right here.
I, for some reason, this is a one-minute game,
thought that he was threatening checkmate,
and so I said, okay, I'm abandoning my rook.
I'm sorry, I'm abandoning my knight,
but you're going to have to rearrange,
and so that's what I did.
He comes back, and now I have to defend myself
from this attack. He's trying to skewer me,
and I also got to defend here
so that I can then launch my attack on the king side.
We'll see what happens.
I stop, and then I'm attacking this guy.
I'm saying, hey, I don't really like that you're getting in my space.
He comes back. I attack the queen, which is not the best move,
and now I should have put on the defile and made some things happen.
Fortunately, he does not take the advantage to kick my knight away,
and so I'm able to make this move.
Why? So that I can make that move next,
and so he doesn't checkmate me on the next move
and not play this f5 winning my knight and the game,
and now I'm able to finally play this move.
Indeed, it is the best move, and here we start cooking.
All right, so we're breaking this connection on the e file,
and we're also forcing his rook to move up,
and then I would move here.
Then you'd have to move away,
and I'm going to win that pawn eventually.
He just abandons it for some reason.
I think he's trying to save here and mobilize his queen.
Doesn't work, though, and watch this ending, folks.
Boom. This is a classic mate.
What's the best move? Indeed, it is a double check.
And why does he move here?
Well, that's checkmate, and that's what happened in the game,
but the reason why he moves there is because if he moves here,
I sacrifice the queen, rook takes, and it's checkmate smothers mate.
Thanks so much for watching. Like and subscribe.