Herpes hits hard. Painful genital ulcers, multi-giant cells would be primary HSV. You treat it with a
cyclovir. So these are primary genital herpes. You'll see like the positive Sanktsmere.
You'll see a rash on the genitals and you should be giving them a cyclovir which is a nucleoside
analogue and it's converted into a cyclovir monophosphate principally through the virus
encoded thymidine kinase. That's definitely important. So basically it gets incorporated
into the DNA chain and then it terminates the DNA sequence. That's how it stops primary genital
herpes. So HSV is stopped with it. Buzzwords, painful vesicles in the arithmetic base,
tendering guenolimb adenopathy, Sanktsmere, multi-nucleated giant cells associated with HSV2,
primarily genital, neonatal, HSV, HIV co-infections. The link exists because HSV disrupts epithelial
integrity and recruits your CD4 positive T cells. So you get the direct contact. The virus
replicates through the DNA polymerase, through thymidine kinase, kinase, then it's latent,
and then a cyclovir is needed to kill it.
All right, so we've got to get that chain termination. Practice question, 24-year-old man,
painful lesions, clusters of vesicles, arithmetic base. So that's already herpes simplex virus,
Sanktsmere, they're giving us that as well. Oral medications used, what's the mechanism?
It requires viral thymidine kinase for activation. All right, so acyclovir and its pro-drugs are
nucleoside analogs that rely on HSV encoded thymidine kinase for activation, ensuring selectivity.
They're phosphorylated, and then they can inhibit the viral DNA polymerase.
So inhibits neuraminase, that's going to be, oh, Ssantimivir, that's like a flu agent,
UU for people who got the flu, promotes up-regulation into ferron synthesis, immune boost pathway,
and not going to be antiviral at all. Inhibits viral protease, that's HIV and HCV drug classes.
Like, Indenivir, that's a retroviral assembly.
Influenza A is the blocks of viral encoding,
mantidine is a medication that does that. If you found this helpful, like and subscribe,
we'll see you in the next video.